walsh.edu 2018-08-31

# Privacy Policy

Walsh University is committed to ensuring the privacy and accuracy of your confidential information. Therefore, Walsh University collects no personally identifiable information about you unless you affirmatively choose to make such information available to us. Personal information provided by visitors, such as email addresses or information submitted via online forms, is used by Walsh University to assist individual visitors as necessary. This assistance may involve redirecting an inquiry or comment to another Walsh University individual or unit better suited to provide resolution. Your information will be used to execute the immediate transaction and service(s) and for other business needs of Walsh University related to the transaction or service.

Walsh University may use third party vendors to help us provide services to you. However, Walsh University will not provide any of your personal information to third parties without your permission, and we will not sell any personal information to third parties for purposes of marketing, advertising, or promotion.

## Cookies

Walsh University analyzes its Web server log files to collect summary information about visitors to its website so that we can track the use of our website to make improvements. Walsh University also subscribes to Google Analytics, which uses cookies to collect anonymous traffic data. A cookie is a file written to your computer's hard drive that is often used to remember information about preferences and pages you have visited. This information is stored and used in the aggregate only, and is not under normal circumstances used to contact you personally. This information allows us to see which areas of our websites are most visited and helps us improve the quality of your online experience by recognizing and delivering more of the most desired features and services. Additional non-personally identifiable information, including but not limited to, domain type, browser version, service provider, and IP address, may also be collected, which will provide information regarding the general use of our website.

If you submit personally identifiable information to our website, Walsh University may use cookies to keep track of such information so that you will not need to reenter this information during subsequent visits. You may set your internet browser preferences to notify you when you receive a cookie or you may decline acceptance of cookies. If you decline acceptance of cookies, however, you may experience less than optimal performance from our website.

## Sharing of Information and Public Records Requests

Although Walsh University does not actively share information, in some cases we may be compelled by law to release information gathered from our Web servers. Walsh University will only share information about you to other parties when one or more of the following conditions apply:

  * We have your consent to share the information.
  * We need to share your information to provide the service or product you requested.
  * We need to send your information to companies who work on behalf of Walsh University to provide a service or product to you.
  * The information in question is considered directory information consistent with Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act ("FERPA") regulations.
  * We need to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or any other legal process.
  * We find it necessary to protect and defend the legal rights and/or property of Walsh University.

Walsh University also complies with FERPA, which prohibits the release of educational records without student permission. For more details on FERPA, currently enrolled students should consult the Walsh University Catalog and Student Handbook. Walsh University, in accordance with FERPA, has designated the following information as "directory information." The University may release directory information to anyone without the student's consent unless the student requests otherwise in writing to the Office of the Registrar prior to the first day of the academic semester or term in which the request is to become effective. This will remain in effect until removed by the student.

Information Walsh University may release, unless the student wishes all information to be withheld, includes:

(1) Name; (2) address, both local and permanent; (3) telephone number, both local and home; (4) major field of study; (5) participation in officially recognized Walsh University activities and sports; (6) weight and height of members of athletic teams; (7) dates of attendance; (8) enrollment status; (9) degrees and awards received; and (10) previous educational agencies and/or institutions attended.

The student has the right to consent to disclosures of personally identifiable information contained in the educational records, except to the extent that FERPA authorizes disclosure without consent. One exception, which permits disclosure without consent, is disclosure to Walsh University officials with legitimate educational interests. Personally identifiable information is information that, if disclosed, would make a student's identity easily traceable, such as a student's Social Security number.

Walsh University is equally committed to protecting the privacy of all visitors to our website and also complies with the applicable provisions of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act and the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act.

## Encryption

Walsh University uses encryption on its secured websites, such as MyWalsh, to prevent third parties from accessing sensitive data, such as passwords. You are normally required to enter a unique Walsh Username and Password when you request data about yourself to ensure that you are a member of the Walsh University community.

## International Visitors

If you are visiting the Walsh University website from a location outside of the United States, your connection will be through and to servers located in the United States. All information you provide to the Walsh University website will be maintained in web servers and/or internal systems located within the United States.

## Links to Other Websites

Our website may contain links to other independently run websites. Please be aware that Walsh University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other websites.

## Security

This Web site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control.

## Disclaimer of Liability

The information contained in this policy explains the internet privacy policy and practices that Walsh University has adopted for its official website and related Web pages. In legal terms, it shall not be construed as a contractual promise, and Walsh University reserves the right to amend it at any time without notice. If Walsh University's privacy policy changes, such changes will be reflected on this page. By continuing to use our websites after a change is posted, you agree to the applicable version of this privacy policy. Please refer to this policy before making a transaction or sharing personal information. Neither Walsh University nor any of its units, schools, divisions, programs, employees, or agents shall be held liable for any improper or incorrect use of the information described and/or contained in the Walsh University website and assumes no responsibility for anyone's use of the information.

 _This Privacy Policy is effective June 1, 2013._
